Posting on social media, even
if you do it every day, is not marketing.
And I'm sure by now many of you have tried
just putting out more social media
content, and you're sat there thinking,
"Where are all the clients?" I come from a
background of fitness,
and some people go to the gym and train,
and some people go
to the gym and exercise.
When you go to the gym and train,
you're methodic,
strategic, you follow a program,
and every session has a desired outcome.
When you go to the gym and you exercise,
you kind of just go, jump on a treadmill,
get a bit of a sweat on.
And the people that exercise always want
to look like
people that train, the same way
that people that post on social media want
the
results of those
that actually have some form of marketing
strategy.
I'll be honest with you,
I've watched five,
maybe even 10 videos today from
some of the top marketers on YouTube,
and I don't get it.
I don't know what the hell they're on
about.
They use all these big words
and fancy things, belief, strategies,
systems,
success, results.
I don't think I'm intelligent enough to
actually
understand what they're on about.
But good news is,
I have a marketing system for my own
business.
And at the moment,
it's averaging me about 7,000 US dollars a
day.
So rather than trying to sound smart like
all the other plebs on the internet, why
don't I just walk you through how I do it?
Because even if we have separate
businesses, there
are going to be components of
this that if you apply to your business,
there could be a world where you do post
content and clients come out the other
side, but only if you get these stages
right.
I'm well aware on the outside it might
just look like I'm posting content,
but I'm going to talk you through the post
and ghost method, which is averaging me
about 7,000 US dollars a day,
which works out about two
and a half million a
year.
And this is from only one of my
businesses.
This is the framework
that I'm sure you're getting sick of.
Socials, emails, landing page, client.
The main misconception is that this
is what's happening.
And there's a little bit more complexity
to it than just get their email, send them
to a landing page. So let's get into it.
One of the most common terminologies
is cold into warm.
What we're trying to do
is start off with cold leads
and warm them up.
So here's my strategy.
My main strategy at the moment is YouTube,
and my main
reason for this,
some new data has emerged
that people need to spend seven hours in
front of you to consider becoming a
client.
Now, straight from the off,
it doesn't have to be YouTube videos.
Webinars could be great for this.
Live streams are amazing for this.
If you combine the both of them,
you have something they call a workshop.
And I'll be honest, short-form content
is how you get discovered on social media.
YouTube is the place
that you take someone to really get the
point across that you
know what you're on about.
So let's break this down.
Out of every 100 people
that watch a video,
probably about five to 10 of them are
going to go to the description to look at
your offer.
At the moment, I'm running three.
There's a 30-day lead magnet.
There's a short-form content mastery
course.
But I've also created a PT starter kit,
which is just a longer version of this
that's just for personal trainers.
Because my first business
was a personal training business,
it's low-hanging fruit.
This is actually a lead magnet,
but it's $99 because, well,
it's flipping good.
At the moment,
there's also a little bundle in there
where you get those two, plus
an email marketing course for 199.
So this is my organic means of getting
people to those things.
This is the first part of the funnel.
This is the second part.
I'm also going to underline these in red
to represent that they have some paid ads
in the background.
We'll pay for some people to get into the
email flow, some
people to get into the short-form content
mastery course, some people to get into
the bundle. These people
are going to get a good experience for
free.
Maybe they're not ready to buy,
and they just don't trust me yet.
These two cohorts of people here probably
trust me enough to buy, but not enough to
buy the mentorship. The mentorship
is two and a half thousand US dollars,
lifetime
access.
I'll also work with people in there
through Discord.
I'm in there all day, every day.
Some people will go from here to here,
but I'd
actually much rather they went across to
one of these.
At the moment across these,
we're seeing about an 8% conversion rate
joining into
the mentorship.
And since I last did one of these videos,
we've started doing
something else.
My primary effort goes into making these
YouTube videos, and we now
use a software called Opus Pro,
which means that Declan can take this
video, chuck
it into this, and create clips.
And I've now asked him to make three a
day.
Those clips have now grown my business
Instagram to 19.2K already.
I do flirt some of these across to my main
page for granted.
We've even started putting these clips
onto a James Smith business TikTok.
Now,
one thing that we've started doing
that really made us get a bump in revenue
is this. We've implemented a chatbot.
If someone comments a certain word,
we'll say, "Hey, DM us that word,
and we will
send you the full episode."
Which means some people
are going to watch a short-form
video, end up watching the full video,
accumulate close to seven hours,
maybe head
down to the description
and take one of the offers.
But here's the smart part.
Each chatbot now finishes with a question.
"Is there anything you'd like to ask me?
Would you like to know anything else about
the courses?" Someone might say, "Oh,
how much is the mentorship? Oh,
how much does this cost?
Oh." But the main purpose of these
questions is to show people to these
courses they may not know about because
they may not have absorbed the amount of
YouTube content necessary to go to the
description to understand it.
"Hi, do you only work with PTs?" "No,
but to get a feel for the information
that I
can give you,
check out the 30-day lead magnet."
If you get that via email, which
you can, guess what?
In the description to this video,
you probably know that I
teach things you can apply to any
business.
"I've just qualified as a PT." Check out
the PT starter kit.
"I haven't got two
and a half thousand dollars yet to commit
to a course." Do the
short form content mastery.
Hopefully you will soon.
And then again, of course,
some people will naturally just end up in
the
mentorship. Now, the thing is,
we're not actually selling in the DMs.
We're selling in the YouTube content.
We're selling in the 30-day autoresponder,
and we're actually selling in the
courses.
So whether you want free information
and you're willing to sit for 12
minutes to watch a video,
whether you want free information
that can be drip fed to
you over 30 days,
or whether you want information
that you get in a paid course.
The sales isn't happening here.
The sales is happening across the whole
ecosystem.
That's what makes this marketing.
The next part in the mentorship
is about really just delivering a fucking
amazing
job.
People say they want to give you financial
freedom.
They want to give you whatever.
The main thing I want to give people in
the
mentorship is a return on investment.
I want them to earn
that money back as fast as physically
possible, because if I
can get that money back in the matter of a
few weeks, months, I think that's the
first initial great feeling where people
will have good things to say about you,
and it'll just feed back into the
ecosystem.
Catherine Sargent getting her first TikTok
to 20,000 views.
I'm on full rent in the gym,
managed to cover
that in the first 10 days of the
month. Next three weeks,
cash in the pocket. Miniscule win.
Signed an online client,
emailed every day since January.
First after buying the email advantage.
Made the autoresponder two weeks ago.
Someone followed me recently,
signed up the emails,
and bought on day two.
Got serious about YouTube at the start of
the year.
Had 1,700 followers,
now at 15,000 this morning.
And that flow of customers has added
nicely to my email list,
now at 5,000 plus.
So the reason I call this a post
and ghost is when I wake up in the
morning, I
serve the mentorship. I make sure
that everyone gets a response.
Then at the latter part of the day,
all I need to focus on
is putting out a good
YouTube video. The packaging's good on it.
People are going to watch it.
A certain amount of people that
are going to watch it
are going to go to the
description.
They're going to go into the ecosystem of
paid and free things.
Those that don't know it
or haven't seen it there will potentially
get it on their
explore feed in short-form content where,
again, if they want the full episode,
they can watch the full episode. And
if they don't want the full episode, they
might just get the links
that they need over to a product
that we have.
One of your last concerns
is probably why do you email people every
day for 30
days?
Why don't you just give them an e-book in
one go?
I don't just want to give someone a good
day or a good couple of days.
I want to turn up
and impact someone's day every day for a
month, because that is
closer to what this is. I'll be honest,
the majority of people in here don't get
any real tangible results in the first few
weeks.
It takes probably two months before they
get their first proper win, six months
till their life's changed quite a lot,
and a year later where it looks like
they're
showing off. When I was a PT client,
I didn't work with someone for five hours
a
day. I'd see them for half an hour
or an hour,
once or twice a week over the course
of a month.
When it comes to a support structure,
you don't give everyone
everything in one go
and just expect them to get through it.
You give them little nuggets
that can help them on their journey.
This is also closer to what this is.
You're probably going to watch 10 YouTube
videos, maybe even 30 clips, before even
considering one of these.
Marketing needs regular touchpoints.
Marketing needs an accumulation of value.
Marketing needs to be wherever they
are and having something for them.
Marketing is appreciating not everyone
is going to pay you the big bucks for your
big thing,
and you might need to give them something
smaller to prove to them
you're not shit. Marketing
is you focusing your efforts in one place
and
people maneuvering through the system,
whichever suits them best.
Not you best, suits them best.
Whether someone just watches YouTube,
cool.
Whether someone watches YouTube
and only pays me $99, cool.
If someone watches YouTube,
only ends up reading my emails,
never does anything
that gives me any money, cool.
If anyone ends up joining my mentorship,
cool.
If anyone gets a return on investment,
super cool.
I created all of this so I can just focus
on the one thing that I'm good at,
this part of the marketing.
And as I get better at this,
my channel's at 25,000
now. When that gets to 100,000,
this all grows.
When that gets to a million,
this all grows. Posting is not marketing.
This is marketing.
That's how you can end up posting on
social media and end up
getting clients at the back of it.
But when it comes to posting, what to say,
and
especially what to say in the first 10
seconds, there is a niche that
is exploding
on social media,
and it's changing the way that people
are starting their content.
And if we could just learn the approach
that's getting them millions of views, we
could transform our content strategy
and our business behind it.
And to understand what they're doing
and why it's working, you'll need to watch
this video here.